埃德∶杰森,凌晨好.
Ed: Top of the morning to you.Jason.
杰森∶喂!埃德,凯特.埃德!!埃德,你们怎么会进来的?
Jason: Hi Ed, Kate.Ed!!Ed, what are you doing here?
埃德∶从垫子下面找到你们的钥匙;哦,对了,
Ed: Got your key out from under the mat; first place a burglar would look,
窃贼第一个要找的地方就是那里.
by the way.
凯特∶我想用徽波炉,但是我弄的爆炸了.
Kate: I tried to use the micro wave, but I blew something up.
杰森∶麦琪,
Jason: Maggie!!Your folks have favoured us with another one of their surprise
你家人又用另一个突然拜访给我们送来了礼物!
visits!
埃德∶这一次我总算知道他在说什么了.
Ed: For once the head shrinker knows what he's talking about.
凯特:如果你告诉我灭火器在那里,
Kate: If you'd tell me where the fire extinguisher is,
我很乐意做早饭.
I'd be happy to cook breakfast.
麦琪∶爸爸,你在这里干什么?
Maggie: Daddy, what are you doing here?
凯特∶玛格丽特,
Kate: Margaret, we did not come all this way to see you;
我们可不是一路赶来看你们的;我们是来看望孙子孙女们的.
we came to see our grandchildren.
埃德∶开萝尔!本!迈克尔!!
Ed: Carol!Ben!Front and centre!!Michael!
杰森∶当他们走后再叫醒我.
Jason: Wake me when they're gone.
麦琪∶杰森,那样是不够礼貌的.
Maggie: Jason, that's not polite.
开萝尔∶外婆,外公,喂!!
Carol: Grandma, Grandpa, hi!
迈克∶星期六早晨,怎么这么吵吵闹闹的!
Mike: Ah come on, it's Saturday morning, for crying out loud!
麦琪∶迈克,你们的祖父母在这儿.
Maggie: Ah Mike, your grandparents are here.
凯特:你们的祖父母也一样.
Kate: Oh, your grandfather's the same way,
until he's had his morning sit-down.
埃德∶凯特,我认为没有人对那些感兴趣.
Ed: Kate, I don't think anyone's gonna be interested in that.
总之,我知道你们急切想知道我们为什么会在这儿.
Anyway, I know you're dying to know why we're here.
杰森∶还有要呆多久.
Jason: And for how long.
埃德∶前几天,我们和律师立定了遗嘱...
Ed: The other day, we went over our will with our lawyer...
麦琪∶妈妈,爸爸,你们生病了吗?
Maggie: Mom, Daddy, are you sick?
埃德∶你知道的,
Ed: Well, you know, your mother's always been a little ify.
你妈妈总是有一点不舒服.除此外我们都很健康.
Well, other than that we're in perfect health.
我们现在要做的是把我们的遗产送给孙子们.
Well, what we've decided to do is give our grandkids their bequests now.
凯特∶我们决定在活着的时候来享受这份快乐.
Kate: The point is, why wait until we're dead to enjoy ourselves.
埃德∶给,给,迈克尔,给.
Ed: Here.Here, and Michael, here.
本∶是现金.
Ben: It's cash.
迈克∶哇,很多的现金.
Mike: Wow!A whole lot of cash.
开萝尔∶5000美金.
Carol: Five thousand Dollars.
埃德∶你们想怎么花就怎么花.
Ed: And you can spend it any way you want.
本和迈克∶哦!谢谢!谢谢!谢谢!谢谢!
Ben and Mike: Oh, thank you!Thank you!Thank you!Thank you!
本和迈克∶谢谢!谢谢!
Ben and Mike: Thank you!Thank you!
麦琪∶快放开你们的外公,他无法呼吸了.
Maggie: Let your grandfather go; he can't breathe.
埃德∶凯特,我说过这肯定比到爱尔兰去更有意思,对吗?
Ed: Kate, I told you this would be more fun than going to Ireland.
麦琪∶哦,爸爸,等等;在我们被带走...
Maggie: Oh, Daddy, hold on here; before we get carried away...
开萝尔∶我们不能接受它.
Carol: We can't accept it.
迈克∶我要!
Mike: I'll take it!!
本∶我也要!
Ben: I'll take it!!
杰森∶不像话.
Jason: This is no way to act.
迈克∶爸爸,我们和你平分.
Mike: Dad, we'll split it with you.
本∶对.
Ben: Yeah.
埃德∶不你不能!这钱属于开萝尔.
Ed: No you won't!This money belongs to Carol.
麦琪∶爸爸,我们当中没有一个人想要你们的钱.
Maggie: Daddy, none of us want your money.
迈克∶妈妈!妈妈!你做什么 ?
Mike: Mom!Mom!What are you doing?
凯特∶麦琪,让他们拿走吧!让他们拿走吧!
Kate: Let go of the money, Maggie!Let go of the money!
埃德:听你妈妈的!别动!
Ed: Listen to your mother!!!Nobody move!!
马格利特,
Margaret, this is our money,
这是我们的钱,
it was our decision to give it to the grandchildren,
我们决定要不要还给爷爷奶奶,你不要管.
and this doesn't involve you at all!
迈克:对.
Mike: Enough said!
麦琪∶但是爸爸,你们不是攒钱到爱尔兰去的吗?
Maggie: But Daddy, I thought you were saving you money to go to Ireland.
埃德∶哦!我胡说八道想到哪里都可以啦.
Ed: Oh, I can get crocked on Stout anywhere.
.凯特∶他有.
Kate: He has
埃德∶好了,孩子们,给你们;想怎么花就怎么花.
Ed: Right, Kids, here it is; and you can spend it as you will.
迈克和本∶谢谢!
Mike and Ben: Thanks!
麦琪∶别碰那些钱!杰森,帮帮我!
Maggie: Don't touch that money!Jason, help me out here.
杰森∶让我来告诉你们该怎么做,我们应该像一家人一样,
Jason: OK, alright!I'll tell you exactly what we should do, is just sit down,
坐下来,好好的解决这件事.
together as a family and talk this out.
埃德:哦!可以,你可以收他们5000块的会议费.
Ed: Oh sure and then you charge them five thousand Dollars for the session.No siree bob.
麦琪:爸爸,我不能眼看着孩子们浪费你一生的积蓄.
Maggie: Daddy I will not sit still and watch my kids squander your life-savings.
本∶什么叫做挥霍?
Ben: What does squander mean?
开萝尔∶是说你根本不考虑你是否需要,就乱花你的钱.
Carol: It means spending you money on whatever you want, whether you need it or not.
埃德∶凯特,你相信吗?
Ed: Kate, can you believe this?
凯特∶对,她一直都是一个一毛不拔的孩子.
Kate: Yes, she's always been a sour child.
.埃德∶你唯一的女儿不想接受你遗嘱中的遗产,真是让人觉得难过.
Ed: It's a dark day when your only daughter won't honour your last will in testament
麦琪∶哦...
Maggie: Oh...
埃德∶我想是我过去为你修理自行车的时候,
Ed: I guess when I used to fix your bicycle I couldn't have done much
修的不够好.
of a job.
麦琪∶哦爸爸...
Maggie: Oh Daddy...
埃德∶我经常提前下班去看你上芭蕾舞表演,
Ed: Just when I used to get off work early so that I could come to
这还不够.
your ballet recitals, that wasn't enough.
麦琪∶哦,别,我...我..
Maggie: Oh, please, I...I...
埃德∶我打第二份工,以便能把你送到好的高中.
Ed: And when I took that second job to put you through a highly academic high-school.
麦琪∶好了,好了.孩子们可以拿这些钱了.
Maggie: OK.Ok, the kids can keep the money.
麦琪∶太好了!
Mike: Alright!
本∶是!
Ben: Yes!
迈克∶本,那你要怎么花你的钱?
Mike: Yes!Benny, so how are you gonna spend yours?
本∶我不知道,但是我觉得挥霍听起来真是很不错的.
Ben: I don't know but that squander thing sounds pretty good to me.
迈克∶开萝尔,你最好快去下面的银行;你傻在这里,
Mike: Carol, you better get down to the bank; I mean by hanging out here,
已经少了16的利息了.
you've already blown like sixteen Cents in interest.
开萝尔∶我不喜欢.
Carol: I don't like this.
杰森∶埃德,
Jason: Ed, I gotta hand it to you;
我不得不佩服你;我从来没见过有哪对父母这样来使孩子内疚的.
I have never seen a parent use guilt the way you do.
埃德∶我也承认我是好样的.
Ed: Yep.I gotta admit, I'm good.
杰森:我是说,
Jason: I mean, Mike and Carol are over eighteen,
迈克和开萝尔都已经过了十八岁了,
but I just can't let my thirteen year old son walk out of this house,
但是我不能让我的十三岁的儿子自己拿五千美元出去花.
Ed, with five thousand Dollars in his pocket.
埃德∶哈哈哈,已经出去了.
Ed: Ha ha ha, you're too late.
杰森∶本!本!本!
Jason: Ben!Ben!Ben!
加里∶你想怎么花就怎么花?
Gary: Wow!And you can spend it any way you want?
本∶是的.我鞋里还有4000美金.
Ben: Yeah.And I got four thousand more in my shoes.
加里∶哇,你看起来像白领.
Gary: Wow!Hey, I thought you looked collar.
本∶臭虫,给你.别找零钱了.
Ben: Here's Stinky.Keep the change.
臭虫∶本,以前还从来没有人派出租车来接过我.
Stinky: Ben, no-one's ever sent a cab for me before.
本∶这才是开始呢,只是开始.
Ben: This is only the beginning, Stink man, only the beginning.
推销员∶你真的喜欢吧?哈!
Salesman: So, you really like this baby, huh?
迈克∶看起来有点旧.
Mike: Well, it looks a little beat-up.
推销员∶破旧?不,不,
Salesman: Beat up?Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
不,不,不.
This machine has been completely reconditioned by my own skilled technicians.
这辆车是经过我们熟练的技术人员改装的.要1500买的话,跟偷没有什么区别了.
It's a steal at fifteen hundred.
迈克∶事实上,我可以出更高一点的价钱.
Mike: Well, actually, I can spend a little bit more than that.
推销员∶谢天谢地,1500太便宜了吧?
Salesman: Thank God, for fifteen hundred, all you get bupkiss, right?
4700,我可以把轮子后面的豪华车卖给你.
Now, for forty seven
hundred, I can put you behind the wheel of this little cherry here
迈克∶哦,这个还差不多.
Mike: Oh, boy, this is more like it.
推销员∶哦,我说4700了吗?我的意思是说5700.
Salesman: Oh, did I say forty seven hundred?I meant fifty seven.
推销员2∶出去!我的意思是说,呆在外面!!
Salesman 2: Get out!And this time I mean, stay out!!
佛瑞德∶难道不允许男人们看一下吗?
Fred: Can't a gentleman browse any more?
推销员2∶炸面圈是专门为客户提供的!
Salesman 2: Mr.Dognuts are for customers, pop!
你根本不打算买车.
You had no intention of buying a car.
佛瑞德∶就这态度,我才不买呢.
Fred: Not with that attitude, I don't.
迈克∶佛瑞德!佛瑞德,你还好吗?
Mike: Fred!Fred, how you doing?
推销员2∶你认识这乞丐?
Salesman 2: You know this bum?
迈克∶是的!佛瑞德在红灯路口给我洗了好几年的挡风玻璃.
Mike: Oh yeah!Fred's been washing my wind shields at stop-lights for years.
佛瑞德,你过的怎么样?
Fred, how you been?
佛瑞德∶一般般.谢谢你的问候.
Fred: Just dandy.Thank you very much for the inquiry.
我可以请你吃个炸面圈吗?
Can I offer you a doughnut?
推销员∶保罗,叫警察!
Salesman: Paul, call the cops!
佛瑞德∶还是下一次吧.
Fred: Perhaps another time.
推销员∶我说4700块,是一个错误,是我犯了一个错误,因此...
Salesman: OK, I said forty seven hundred, and that was a mistake, but it was my mistake, so...
迈克∶借过.佛瑞德,我搭你回去吧?
Mike: Excuse me.Fred, you need a lift home?
佛瑞德∶谢谢你的好意,我自己可以回去.
Fred: Oh, that's very kind, but I have transportation.
推销员∶4500块,我一分钱也不赚.
Salesman: Forty five hundred, but I don't make a Nickel on it.
迈克∶抱歉.
Mike: Excuse me.
推销员∶嗨!那我们的交易还要不要做?
Salesman: Hey, what about the deal here?
迈克∶不必担心,我会回来的.
Mike: Don't worry, I'll be back.
推销员∶所有的人都说我会回来的,
Salesman: I'll be back, that's what they all say.
我多么希望我是议员.
Days like this, I almost wish I'd stayed a congress man.
推销员2∶我也是.
Salesman 2: You and me both.
杰森∶苏利纨太太,我不明白你怎么会让出租车接走臭虫,
Jason: Ah now, I don't understand Mrs Sullivan you just...
而不问他要去哪里.是,
You let Stinky just get into a cab without asking him where he was going.
我是让本带着5000美金出了门,也没有问他的去处.
Yes I did let Ben out the door with five thousand Dollars without asking
但是....
where he was going, but that...Technically.
不是有意的.好吧,
Alright, well if you hear from them just let us know the name of the country
如果你知道他们的消息,马上通知我们他们在买哪个国家.
they're buying.
麦琪∶都是你的过错.
Maggie: This is all your fault, you know.
杰森∶我的错!为什么?
Jason: My fault!Why?
麦琪∶我不能阻止他们;我正在愧疚的哭泣.
Maggie: Well, I couldn't stop them; I was crippled with guilt.
杰森∶我也从来没有想让本出这个门的.
Jason: Look, I never even intended to let Ben out the door.
麦琪∶哦,这么说来你一点责任也没有了?
Maggie: Oh, so you're ducking all responsibility?
杰森∶是!是!我不应该由于你爸爸让你哭泣而分心.听着,试着想想我这句话的隐含意思,而不是表面意思,因为...你!埃德!全部都是你的错!
Jason: Oh, OK!OK!I shouldn't have been distracted by your father playing you like a bass fiddle.And...err...now listen, if you'd try to think of the meaning behind my words here, instead of the words themselves, because...You!Ed!This is all your fault!
埃德∶我请你原谅.
Ed: I beg your pardon.
杰森∶因为你,我13岁的儿子带着他连想都不敢想的那么多钱不知道去了哪里,
Jason: Well because of you my thirteen year old son is God-knows-where,
也不知道会做出什么事情.
doing God-knows-what with more money than he ever imagined.
埃德∶难道不好吗?啊哈!别再内疚了,快出去找你的儿子吧.
Ed: Yeah, and ain't it grand.Aha!Got over your guilt and ready to go
out and hit the mall, huh
开萝尔∶外公,花费这笔钱的想法,让我觉得很悲伤.
Carol: Grandpa, the thought of spending this money, makes me very sad.
埃德:悲伤?
Ed: Sad?
开萝尔∶因为它迫使我意识到,总有一天我会失去你们.
Carol: Because it forces me to realise there'll be a time when you're
如果你真的爱我的话,你最好还是把钱收回.
not around.Look, if you love me you'll just take the money back.
.埃德∶好吧宝贝儿.
Ed: Sure honey
开萝尔∶谢谢.
Carol: Thank you.
埃德∶但是我们不要告诉你的外婆.否则会使她心碎的.
Ed: But let's not tell your grandmother.This would break her heart.
开萝尔∶什么?
Carol: What?
埃德∶哦,自从你落地的那一天,
Ed: Oh, she's been waiting for this since the day you were born.
她就一直在等待着.她为你拿来她自己亲手织的毯子.
The day that she bought you that blanket that she knitted.
开萝尔∶毯子先生?
Carol: Mr.Blanky?
埃德∶就是那个.
Ed: The very same.
开萝尔∶我不知道了.
Carol: Well, I had no idea.
埃德∶当然,如果这笔钱让你感觉不舒服...我是说,
Ed: Of course, if this money makes you feel uncomfortable...
这个怎么能与一个老人的心相提并论呢?啊!你说呢?
I mean how does that compare to an old lady's heart?Ah!Are you sure?
开萝尔∶外公,你这是激将法.
Carol: Grandpa, you're pushing it.
迈克∶就在这里好了.
Mike: I'm right here.
佛瑞德∶要外套吗?
Fred: Coat?
迈克∶不用,谢谢,我穿自己的就好了.
Mike: Err...no thanks, I'll keep mine on.
佛瑞德∶我是说要不要多加一件;有风从这里穿过,所以这里可比外面还要冷呢.也许这个冬天我应该去暖和的佛罗里达.
Fred: No, I mean another one; the wind whips through here and makes it a
lot friskier than it is outside.You know, maybe this winter I'm gonna make it
to sunny Florida
迈克∶哦,你是从佛罗里达来的?
Mike: Oh, are you from Florida?
佛瑞德∶不是的,但是我听说,
Fred: No, but the word on the street is,
they got great garbage behind Burt Reynold's dinner theatre
Mike: Well I guess Lorny Ashen must be pretty handy in the kitchen
佛瑞德∶你觉得很奇怪吗?呵,我们走运了!你吃过午餐没有?
Fred: Does that surprise you?Well, we're in luck!Did you eat lunch yet?
迈克∶不用,谢谢,佛瑞德,我不饿.
Mike: Ah, no.No thanks, Fred, I'm not hungry.
佛瑞德∶当然.我明白.
Fred: Of course.I understand.
迈克∶哦,那就吃一口吧.
Mike: Oh, well maybe just one bite.
佛瑞德∶啊哈!给你.
Fred: Aha!There you go.This is our lucky day!
今天是我们的幸运日!看上去好像是奶油馅的.
Looks like this used to be cream-filled.
迈克∶谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
佛瑞德∶劳埃德,我们多了一个同伴.
Fred: Lloyd, we've got company.
迈克∶你有一只狗.
Mike: You have a dog.
佛瑞德∶别那么大声;房东不允许养狗的.劳埃德,
Fred: Not so loud; the landlord dissaproves.
给,我也给你带了点吃的.
Here Lloyd, I got something for you, too.Hey, I hope that isn't mine.
希望不是我的.要不要我帮你把炸面圈热一下?
Shall I heat up your doughnut?
迈克∶不用,谢谢.
Mike: Ah, no thanks.
(音乐在唱:这是我想要的)
(Music playing: "That's what I want")
加里∶他来了!他来了!
Gary: Here he is!Here he is!
本∶非常感谢伙计!
Ben: Thanks a lot guys!
加里∶这个主意真不错.
Gary: Hey, I think this was a great idea.
用你的钱请大家大吃一顿.
I think every body worked up an appetite spending your money.
本∶我不知道我的钱够不够请所有的人吃.
Ben: I don't know if I can feed these people, man.
I'm not sure if I have enough money!
学生∶你在开玩笑吗?你的右脚的鞋还没有碰过呢.
Student: Are you kidding?You haven't even touched your right shoe.
本∶我已经用了;在骑楼里,在唱片店,
Ben: I sure did; at the arcade, at the record store, at the burger place,
在汉堡包店,在保龄球场...我只有200块了.
at the bowling alley...I only got two hundred Dollars left!
加里∶你是说你一天用了4800块!
Gary: You blew four thousand eight hundred Dollars in one day!
本∶我想是的.
Ben: I guess I did.
学生∶你在想什么?
Student: What the heck were you thinking?
女服务员∶你们要点东西了;最好不要只有一份可乐和60根吸管.
Waitress: You're gonna have to order something;
and it better not be one Cola with sixty straws.
加里∶每人一个汉堡包!
Gary: Burgers for everybody!
朋友∶本!本!本!
Friends: Benny!Benny!Benny!
女服务员∶你肯定你有足够的钱?
Waitress : You sure you got enough money?
本∶啊...给我200块的汉堡包.嗨,这里发生什么事情了?
Ben: Ahh...give me two hundred Dollars worth of burgers.Hey, what's going on here?
老板:祝贺你!
Owner: Congratulations!You are Burger Bar's one millionth customer!
你是汉堡包吧的第一百万个客户!你们所有的用餐都由店方免费招待!
Which means, your order is on the house!
并且还有5000美金的奖金!!!
And I am pleased to present you with five thousand Dollars!!!
本∶不要再给我钱了,我应付不来了.
Ben: No more money, I can't afford.
加里:你不能责怪我.
Gary: Hey, you can't blame 'em man, you're the one who bought their friendship.
臭虫∶没有人知道你赢了5000美金.让我们2个平分.
Stinky: No-one knows you did five thousand.Let's keep it between us.
本∶什么?
Ben: What?
杰森∶嗨!外面发生什么事了?
Jason: Hey, what's going on out there?
本∶爸爸,小心,我给他们买了很多他们根本不需要的东西.
Ben: Dad, be careful, I bought them a lot of things that they could throw.
杰森∶你给他们买东西?
Jason: You bought them things?
加里∶是的,他用他所有的钱给我们买了这些毫无用处的东西.
Gary: Yeah, he blew his whole wad on those ungreatful pigs.
麦琪∶我没听错吧?你所有的钱都花完了?
Maggie: Did I hear that correctly young man, that you blew your whole wad?
本∶是的.
Ben: I did.
麦琪∶哦,比我想像的要糟糕多了.我原本以为最多浪费个100美元,但是没想到早上带着5000美金出去,现在带着...你到底还剩多少?
Maggie: Oh, well this is worse than I imagined.Now I can understand wasting a hundred Dollars, but to leave here this morning with five thousand Dollars and come home with...How much do you have left?
本∶5200美金.
Ben: Five thousand two hundred.
杰森∶肯定的.
Jason: Exactly.
杰森和麦琪∶多少?
Jason and Maggie: What?
本∶我赢的,可以吗?
Ben: I won it, OK?
杰森:本,
Jason: Ben, we're gonna talk about this,
你要来谈谈这个.
just as soon as I get rid of these kids.
加里∶哦,西维尔医生,不要担心,在我们用本的第二个5000美金的时候,我们不会让这些孩子接近本的.
Gary: Oh, don't worry Dr Seaver, we won't let any of those kids near Ben, when we spend his next five thousand Dollars.
麦琪∶你们难道还天真的以为我们会让本再带着5000美金出去吗?
Maggie: Do you boys really think I'm gonna let Ben out that door with this much money, you're crazy.
学生∶你以前做过.
Student: You did before.
麦琪∶是,我们其中的一个允许的.
Maggie: Well, one of us did.
本:我不准备花一分钱.我不想要这些钱.
Ben: I'm not gonna spend a Dime of this money.I don't even want this money.
加里和臭虫∶我们要!我们要!
Gary and Stinky: We'll take it!We'll take it!
杰森∶嘿!嗨!嗨!
Jason: Hey!Hey!Hey!
加里∶是呀,谁要本呢?
Gary: Yeah, who needs Ben?
本∶嗨!如果你们在意只是我的钱,那都给我滚出去!
Ben: Hey!!If all you care about is my money, then get out!
加里:如果我们留下来,我们能得到什么?
Gary If we stay, what do we get?
本∶出去!出去!出去!
Ben: Out!Out!Out!I bought you guys CD's, I bought you guys the Jackets!
我已经给你们买了CD,买了茄克,甚至连内裤也买了!
I even bought you guys underwear!!
麦琪∶你给臭虫买内裤!
Maggie: You bought Stinky underwear!
本∶不,是新的.
Ben: No, it was new.
推销员∶哦,
Salesman: Oh yeah!Oh yeah!
真棒!真棒!
Not many buyers are shrewd enough to test drive a car with the top off
很少有精明的顾客会在大冬天把顶棚打开来试车的.
in the dead of winter.
迈克∶这个应该有顶的,对吗?
Mike: This thing does have a top, right?
推销员∶当然有!你认为我是奸商吗?
Salesman: Of course it does!What sort of business man do you think I am?
属于购买的一部分.
It's on order.
迈克∶伙计,我喜欢这台!
Mike: Boy, I love this thing!
推销员∶我说过的,5700美金,出去说!
Salesman: Like I said, fifty seven hundred, out the door!
迈克∶等一下,你不是说4700吗?
Mike: Well, wait a minute, you said forty seven hundred.
推销员∶成交!让我们签合同.
Salesman: Deal!Let's sign the papers.
迈克∶好.
Mike: OK.
推销员∶迈克!
Salesman: Mike!
迈克∶外面确实很冷.
Mike: It sure is cold out here.
推销员∶恩,
Salesman: Oh, yeah.So,
你会付5700块现金吗?
will you be giving me the whole fifty seven hundred in cash?
杰森∶本,我认为你可能有点极端了.
Jason: Ben, I think maybe you're being a little bit extreme.
本∶我就说希望臭虫和加里能爆炸!
Ben: All I said was that I hope Stinky and Gary explode!
这有什么极端的?
What's extreme about that?
开萝尔∶大家好!
Carol: Hello everybody.
麦琪∶开萝尔,我们现在没时间理你.
Maggie: Carol, we really don't have time for that.
开萝尔∶外婆和外公在哪里?
Carol: Where's Grandma and Grandpa?
麦琪∶希望他们爆炸了.
Maggie: Hopefully they exploded.
杰森∶哦!亲爱的,在厨房里.
Jason: In the kitchen, honey.
麦琪∶你就只关心无关紧要的事情.本,别说了,马上给我下来...
Maggie: You are so helpful on the inconsequential questions.Ben, cut the bologne and get down here...now!!
凯特∶埃迪,没想到我们给孩子们的礼物会让这里的气氛这么煎弩拔张吧?
Kate: Eddy, you don't suppose our gifts to the kids have caused tension around here, do you?
开萝尔∶真好.
Carol: Oh good, you're both here.
你们都在这里.
Well I was out walking for two hours trying to figure out the best way
我在外面走了2个小时,
to spend this money;
终于想到了要怎么样来好好的花这笔钱;我找到了一些东西来做为你给我织毯子的回报.
and I wanted something that could begin to repay you for knitting Mr Blanky.
凯特∶不是我织的,是我找到的.
Kate: I didn't knit that, I found it.
开萝尔∶你什么?
Carol: You what?
埃德∶我们有点偏离主题了.让孩子说下去.
Ed: I think we're getting a little off the track here.Let the child talk.
开萝尔∶恩,你说过我可以怎么开心就怎么花这笔钱的,
Carol: Well, you said I could spend it any way that would make me happy,
这是我买的.
so this is what I bought.
埃德∶到底是什么东西?
Ed: What the heck is this now?
开萝尔∶2张去爱尔兰的头等双程票.
Carol: Two first-class round-trip tickets to Ireland.
凯特∶开萝尔,我不知道你想要爱尔兰.
Kate: Carol, I had no idea you wanted to go to Ireland.
开萝尔∶不是给我买的!是给您二位的.
Carol: Not for me!For you two.
凯特∶给我们?哦,太好了.
Kate: For us?Oh, that's wonderful.
埃德∶如果我想要去爱尔兰旅行,
Ed: Look, if I had wanted to take a trip to Ireland,
我会自己买票去的.
I could have bought it myself.
开萝尔∶当然,你可以自己买,
Carol: Well, sure you could have, but you didn't.
但是你没买,你把钱都给了我们.
You gave the money to us instead.
埃德∶对.那你就无权用这些钱给我们买票.
Ed: Exactly.That's why you had no business doing this.
开萝尔∶你说过你想享受看着我们花这笔钱的乐趣,所以,
Carol: You said you wanted the pleasure of watching us spend it, so here;
现在你看到了;我把钱给了旅行社.
I had the travel agent take it as I gave him the money.
埃德∶我都不知道说什么好宝贝儿.
Ed: Oh.Honey I don't know what to say.
开萝尔∶只是希望您二位在爱尔兰要小心...
Carol: I just want you two to be careful in Ireland because...
因为他们车的行驶方向是刚好和我们相反的.
they drive on the other side of the road there.
凯特∶哦,埃迪,这些年你一直在错误的国家开车.
Kate: Oh, Eddy, all these years you've been driving in the wrong country.
本∶我不明白钱怎么可以让人变得像猪一样.
Ben: I don't understand how money turns people into pigs.
杰森∶本,这是一个开始;让你明白钱改变了你.
Jason: Well, Ben that's a start; just to realise that money did change you.
本∶不是我!是臭虫和加里.
Ben: Not me!Stinky and Gary.
杰森∶本,那你告诉我,他们是怎么强迫你买这些东西的?
Jason: Ben, tell me just how did they force you to buy all these things?
本∶强迫我!他们才不会那么笨!
Ben: Force me!They were very tricky about it.
杰森∶看来都是你自愿的啦,对吗?
Jason: Well, they made it seem like your idea, right?
本∶对.
Ben: Yeah.
麦琪∶这就是原因,本,是你自己要买的.
Maggie: Well there's a reason for that, Ben...it was your idea.
本∶你认为我是故意花掉5000美金的.
Ben: So, you think I blew five thousand Dollars on purpose.
杰森∶不,我想你只是迷失了自己.
Jason: No, I think you probably just lost your head.
本:我?你没有看到臭虫和加里像动物一样抢支票么?
Ben: Me?Didn't you see Stinky and Gary tug on that cheque like animals?
麦琪∶知道,就像今天早上的你和迈克一样.
Maggie: Oh, kind of like you and Mike did, this morning.
本∶哦!是!
Ben: Yeah.Oh!
杰森∶本,你现在得到了一个很重要的认识.
Jason: You just had an important thought there, Ben.
本∶那些东西让我害怕!我不仅花掉了5000美金,
Ben: I was afraid of that.
我也犯下了错误.
So not only did I blow five thousand Dollars, I was wrong too.
麦琪:说得对.
Maggie: That about sums it up.
杰森∶本,接下来,你赢来的5000美金要怎么花呢?
Jason: So, Ben, what are we going to do with all your winnings?
本∶你们可以再让我重新随意花一次.
Ben: Well, you could give me another shot to spend it any way I want.
麦琪∶这是你真实的想法?
Maggie: Is that really what you think?
本∶不是,我只是调节一下气氛而已.
Ben: No, I just figured we all need a good laugh about now.
凯特∶麦琪!杰森!我们的外孙女用她的钱做了一件最美妙的事情.
Kate: Maggie!Jason!Our granddaughter just did the most wonderful thing with her money
本∶不出所料.
Ben: It figures.
开萝尔∶本,你很痛苦吗?
Carol: Ben, you're in pain, how sad.
埃德∶她把我们送到国外去了.
Ed: She's sending us out of the country.
杰森∶开萝尔,不错的主意.
Jason: Carol, that is a terrific idea.
埃德∶你太有先见之明了.
Ed: You're so predictable.
麦琪∶嗨!多学学你的姐姐.
Maggie: Hey, learn something from your sister.
本∶什么?怎么吃饭吗?
Ben: What?How to eat.
开萝尔∶那是什么?
Carol: What's that?
麦琪∶你没买过车吧?
Maggie: You didn't buy a car too, did you?
本∶我应该买的.
Ben: I might have.
迈克∶Ta - da!!坦白说,你们觉得怎么样?
Mike: Ta-da!!Alright, alright, what do you think?Come on, be honest.
杰森∶恩,最少你没有把钱全部花完.
Jason: Well...err...at least you didn't blow all your money at once.
迈克∶什么意思,浪费我的钱?爸爸,这部车真的很不错的.
Mike: What do you mean, blow my money?Dad, this is a great car.
麦琪∶他肯定一子不剩了.
Maggie: He spent every Dime.
埃德∶等等,只等一分钟.迈克,这笔钱你花的开心吗?
Ed: Just wait a damn blooming minute.Mike, are you happy with the way you spent your money?
迈克:爷爷,我从来没有这么高兴过.
Mike: Oh Grandpa, I have never been happier about anything in my whole life.
埃德∶啊,那事情就结了!
Ed: Ah, then case closed!
凯特∶啊我还没弄明白;他买什么了?
Kate: Ah, I don't get it; what did he buy?
埃德∶车道上的一堆废铁.
Ed: The piece of junk in the drive-way.
迈克:告诉你,当我把它拼起来的时候,
Mike: Hey, I'm telling you, once I fix this baby up,
我都不认识它了.
you won't even recognize her.
麦琪∶但是你没钱去装了呀.
Maggie: But you have no money left to fix it up with.
迈克∶啊,零件!
Mike: Ah, details!Details!
零件!我先拿去我们朋友们面前炫耀一下,马上回来.
Look, I'm gonna show this off to my friends, I'll see you later.
麦琪∶哦!杰森,也值了,我不会在怪你了.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, for what it's worth, I don't blame you for this.
杰森∶当然不,谁让他们是我们的孩子呢.
Jason: Of course not; we raised them.
麦琪∶从好的方面看;开萝尔做了一件很漂亮的事情,本呢,
Maggie: Oh well look on the bright side; Carol did something nice,
也得到了一些教训,虽然...
and Ben learned something inspite of himself and...
杰森∶只有迈克还在延续他的没有责任感的完美记录.
Jason: And Mike continued his perfect record of irresponsibility.
麦琪∶对,是完美记录.
Maggie: Well, it is a perfect record.
佛瑞德∶打扰一下!请问迈克尔在家吗?
Fred: Ah, excuse me!Is Michael at home?
麦琪∶啊,你刚好错过了.
Maggie: Ah, you just missed him.
佛瑞德∶哦,讨厌!麻烦你们能不能把这个给他,
Fred: Oh drat!Well, would you give him these, for his new vehicle and...
他的新车可能用得到的...哦,他还忘记拿走我的欠条了.
oh...he forgot my I-owe-you.
麦琪∶3500美元!迈克给你...
Maggie: Thirty five hundred Dollars!Mike gave you...
佛瑞德∶他什么都没有给我.
Fred: He didn't give me nothing.
是一个短期贷款,等我从佛罗里达回来后,
I consider it merely as a short term loan,
我会全额付还给他.
which I will repay in full as soon as I return from Florida.
杰森∶哦,你还知道什么.
Jason: Well, what do you know.
佛瑞德∶我听说那里很多女人都带牙套.
Fred: I hear they got a lot of women there with teeth.
杰森∶牙套?
Jason: Teeth?
佛瑞德∶恩,也许我还可以在那里为劳埃德找到好的伴侣呢.
Fred: Yeah.Maybe I'll even find a little Snouzer for Lloyd.
麦琪∶这才是他的完美记录.杰森∶我从来都没有怀疑过我的儿子..
Maggie: Well, there goes his perfect record.
00:21:55,200
Jason: I never doubted the boy for a minute